Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Why do you always say that
you're gonna be there for me?
That's not true.
You really wouldn't be alone
because I'd like to be with you.
Because I'm happy when
we're together.
- We're not doing anything wrong!
- You're misunderstanding this.
I was just thinking...
Why Juanito didn't even visit me?
How will he?
He and Carmelita were together in the
Governor General's party a few days ago.
Seems like something's
going on between them.
Guide my heart.
I don't want to fall for him.
I don't have doubts about you.
I can see that you don't have
any feelings for Juanito.
And you truly
love my brother, Leandro.
Am I right?
Helena,
when are you planning to make it
official with Juanito?
Carmelita.
- Carmelita.
Don't mind them, Carmela.
You'll just stress yourself.
Helena, when will you say yes to Juanito?
The truth is, I really want him to be...
- Carmelita?
- Carmelita!
Carmelita?
- Water...
- Here, drink.
- [Carmela choking]
- Carmelita?
Drink it. I told you to eat slowly.
Wait!
Drink up.
- Drink some more.
- Wait, hold on.
Ew!
How are you feeling, Carmelita?
I'm alright...
- Do you feel fine?
- Mm-hmm...
Eat slowly. Drink, go on.
Drink some water.
So that's why my date
with Juanito didn't happen.
Because he has another date.
That's Helena and Juanito.
Thank you, Juanito.
I'll go ahead.
Ouch...
Carmelita? Are you still awake?
You sound fast asleep so I
won't wake you up anymore.
But even though you're sleeping,
let me share the story with you.
I can't contain this happiness
within me any longer.
It's been five years
since I first saw Juanito.
I instantly fell in love with him.
I can't understand why my heart
suddenly beat so loudly that night.
Me too.
I can't understand why my heart is
beating for someone I shouldn't fall for.
It was during the feast of San Alfonso.
My eyes were closed while holding a
candle outside the church that night.
You told me, Carmelita, that the
moment I blow out the candles...
I must whisper my wish so that it may be
carried by the smoke up to the heavens.
I hope I'll end up with
the man I'm with right now.
We may not have talked,
but I can feel that our
hearts were beating
in sync with each other.
I immediately asked my
father to talk to Don Mariano
so that Juanito and I can
be arranged for marriage.
But then I heard that he was planning
to study medicine here in Manila.
That's why I told Father
not to push through with it.
I waited for almost five years.
And during those times...
I only see Juanito during the Feast of
San Alfonso and Christmas.
Even after convincing
Father to let me study
with Natasha in the
convent here in Manila..
I only see Juanito once a month.
When he prays here at church...
I'm already satisfied with that.
I'm happy just to be
able to see him from afar
as he reaches for his dreams.
Amazing...
I didn't know someone like her
who could wait and be a martyr for their
love for such a long time can still exist.
That's why I was so heartbroken
when I heard the news that...
You were engaged to Juanito.
I'm lucky that you are such a true friend.
You helped me and Juanito become closer.
I wonder what Juanito's up to?
It's been a week since I last saw him.
Stop, Carmela!
Kill your feelings while it's early.
As they say, prevention
is better than cure.
Oh Shocks! shocks!
Carmelita?
Yes, Mother Olivia?
Do you need anything?
Finish what you're doing.
We're going somewhere.
Alright.
Thank you for coming to my
deceased brother's novena.
Don Valdez, what happened to him?
My brother, Diosdado, has
been missing for two days.
Doña Julieta found him
dead in front of their door.
Without a doubt, he
was murdered by rebels.
They wanted to get revenge on him
since he's a tax collector.
I offer my condolences.
Excuse me, dear. I'll leave you here.
- Mr. Valdez.
- Oh, Juanito.
- - My sincere condolences.
- OMG! Juanito's here too!
Thank you. I'll go ahead.
Miss Carmelita.
Gosh, why do I feel so flushed?
And my heart's beating so loudly.
You don't need to turn away.
Because no matter where you are,
I will always find you.
Carmelita...
The man you love that you
said was in a far away place...
Was he Leandro?
What? How do I
explain to him that
James Gilbert doesn't
exist in this world yet.
Don't worry.
I understand.
First love is difficult to forget.
Especially if it left our hearts wounded.
The conversation
must focus only on him
so that I don't need
to invent more lies.
What does first love mean to you?
Sometimes...
We think that a person would
be our first and last love...
But feelings may change for many reasons -
Distance, exhaustion...
Or maybe your heart is already
beating for someone else.
Maybe... it's just admiration?
Is it admiration or love?
You're in too deep, Carmela!
There's no more cure for
your feelings for Juanito! Fudge!
Is what I'm feeling still right?
Or should I just avoid
this love altogether?
Or would it be better
to just face it head on?
I almost forgot. I need to bring
food and give medicine to Josefina.
Let's meet at the Plaza Santo
Tomas tomorrow afternoon.
I already asked Mother
Olivia and she gave
her permission for us
to watch the theater.
What?! Why did he write it
on the back of his prescription?!
Oh no, what if Helena
misunderstood Juanito's note?
I promised to help them
become a couple after all.
Oh my!
I made sure you'll receive
my message this time.
I apologize if you are startled
by my method of sending it to you.
I want you to meet me
at Plaza Santo Tomas.
I will take you wherever you want to go.
Don't worry. I already asked
permission from Mother Olivia.
I'll be waiting.
I hope you would come.
Please do not be upset if
ever your window breaks.
It's true, it's true, it's true!
Even if I hide before he can see me.
Even if I turn away before he speaks.
Even if I try to change my actions.
But,
I already know
that I cannot escape from the
truth that I am falling in love with him.
And I won't be able to hide it anymore.
But this time, I must tell
Juanito to stay away from me.
I don't want to hurt Helena.
Good morning to you, Miss Carmelita.
Sir... good morning.
I'm not used to you speaking that way.
I think we shouldn't be
formal to each other anymore.
You can call me by my name
and I can do the same myself.
And I also want to be with... Carmela.
There's too many people
here. You might get lost.
And I know this is the
first time you've been here.
Do you want to try these?
Wow... these are delicious!
This is my favorite siomai.
Favorite?
Does Doña Soledad cook Chinese cuisine?
My gosh!
I forgot that in this time, Chinese were
looked down by the Spanish and Filipinos.
What I meant to say is...
from now on, siomai will be my favorite.
Yeah...
Sir. Your cooking is delicious.
I kinda miss this familiar food.
And I also miss my Mom's homemade siomai.
You love painting, don't you?
Come on.
You told me it's imposible for a
person's interest to truly disappear.
Then how about you?
It's a long story.
And right now,
I'm not ready to tell it.
Come.
We're gonna be late for the show.
Thank you for the time you
spared for me, Carmelita.
Me too.
I mean, I'm going to bed soon.
- Wait...
- Actually...
Alright, go ahead.
We have to talk about
Operation Stop Wedding.
You know, my plan about you and Helena.
Before that, I want to give you something.
I hope you'll like it.
What is this for?
Helena?
Helena!
Oh, Helena!
Helena, open your eyes!
Binibining Helena?
Miss!
- Helena? Helena, wake up.
- Miss!
Miss...
- Miss?
- Helena...
Juanito...
Marry me...
- Helena? Helena?
- Miss Helena...
Binibini!
How is Helena's condition, Dr. Hidalgo?
Juanito?
Her heart rate is low and her
breathing is slow, Dr. Hidalgo
What should we do?
Don't worry, Mother Olivia.
I will advise you on what to
do make her recovery faster.
What happened?
Why did you suddenly come here?
I apologize, but I'm not
in the position to say it.
It's alright. I know how
trustworthy you are.
Laura? Your name is Laura, right?
Yes, Laura Isabela.
Is your family from San Alfonso?
I mean, your ancestors.
Don't worry, I'm not a spy.
My family is originally from Tarlac.
My aunt took me to San Alfonso as payment
for my father's debt to the Flores family.
OMG. I know that Daddy is from
Tarlac and he only met Mommy in Manila.
So, Laura is indeed Daddy's ancestor..
I was supposed to serve
Don Joselito's household,
the mayor of our town.
But there's already so
many servants there.
But Don Joselito was
Captain Flores' brother.
It so happens that Miss
Natasha fired their former helper.
that's why my aunt
took me to San Alfonso.
Don't worry.
In just a few years, you'll be
together with your family again.
I have grown fond of my masters.
They treated me
as if I'm family.
So I will be saddened when
the time comes that I must leave.
Helena is kind,
that's why it's hard saying no to her.
Just like Leandro, who
loves Carmelita so much.
It was right for Helena
to trust Carmelita.
And Leandro is also right for loving her.
The only wrong thing is
that I am the one who's here.
I don't deserve their trust.
Miss,
I will only tell this to you.
Since you are Miss Helena's best friend...
The truth is Miss Helena
ran away from home.
The chief of the Civil
Guards is looking for her.
And also the people
working under Captain Flores.
Why did Helena run away?
After arriving at San Alfonso
she and Captain Flores had an argument,
and the Captain slapped her.
That night, I caught her packing
with the intention of running away.
I tried stopping her
but she said she needs
to talk to you and Sir
Juanito here in Manila.
OMG! Is that why she
asked Juanito to marry her?
But why does she need to talk to me?
To ask me to allow them to get married?
Oh! Josefina!
Don't come closer. You
might catch the virus from me!
My body's so strong. Can't you see?
All thanks to my complete
vaccine when I was young.
Shouldn't you be resting now?
We are going home today to attend the
thanksgiving celebration at San Alfonso.
Oh, right. Do you need any help?
Helena?!
Laura?!
Are you inside?!
Miss? Miss Helena!
- Miss!
- Mother Olivia! Helena needs help!
Helena!
- Miss!
- Helena! Helena!
Get out of the way!
Helena!
Maybe Helena's being
possessed by an evil spirit?
Oh no...
Helena... what is happening to you?
I'm going home.
- Are you sure, Miss?
- Yes!
So move quickly! We're leaving!
Helena...
What is the reason behind this?
Don't bother writing to my Father.
I will deliver the message myself.
So that he'll know that his
daughter regained her clarity.
Father...
My daughter!
- Welcome back, my daughter.
- Mother Olivia.
Good day, Don Alejandro.
Doña Soldedad.
Maria.
Father...
I am very sorry.
No worries. Always remember
that I love you all very much.
Oh my gosh. What's happening to me?
I miss my Daddy. Good thing
I still have a father in this time.
By the way, my daughter...
I couldn't understand
this letter you sent me.
Carmelita...
I think you are missing some letters here.
What does ILY mean?
IMY?
Why are you so lazy
writing full words, Carmela?
For sure they'll get weirded out if I say
what's the meaning of IMY, ILY, at TC.
The meaning of ILY is...
I will make sure to stay away from trouble.
And for the others, it just so
happens that the ink ran out.
- Amigo!
- Amigo.
- How are you?
I also fetched Juanito.
So, we meet again.
And I am inviting you all to a
gathering at our humble home.
Father, I don't think
I'm feeling very well.
My friend, we all gladly
accept your invitation.
Thank you very much, my friend.
My friend, I will give you
something you'll surely love.
It is breezy outside.
Carmelita, I hope you feel
at ease here in our home.
Thank you.
Is your heart troubled?
I understand what's
going on with your feelings.
Carmelita, a parent's love for their child
is something no one could measure.
But I understand
that your parents are
looking forward to
your wedding to Juanito.
But I'm also sure that
they have reservations.
Because nothing is
certain in this world, right?
Juanito is kind and gentle.
Because we raised him to
be kind and well-mannered.
And he witnessed the love
between me and his father.
He will love and cherish you forever.
I pray that you may overcome
all the challenges you'll face.
Juanito's bride sure is lucky.
From now on, please treat
me like your own mother.
Doña Juanita? Doña Juanita!
Mother?
What's the matter, Mother?
Nothing. This is nothing, maybe...
Maybe I just need some rest.
Please don't mention
it to your father.
Because I don't want
him to... get worried.
Especially when the Montecarlos are here.
Carmelita, I hope you won't
tell your family because...
It might... ruin their enjoyment of today.
If they are informed that I
am not feeling quite well.
Angelito. Fetch Mother's medicines.
Let us take Mother to her room.
Yes, brother.
How's Doña Juanita?
Mother's already asleep.
Her heart's weak that's why
she must not exert herself.
Maybe he got exhausted
preparing for my homecoming.
Miss...
is Theresita with you?
What are you whispering about?
Mother said, she wants Miss
Carmelita to have a tour of our house.
I'll do it, Angelito.
You go and watch Mother.
Let's go, Miss Carmelita.
Where are we going?
Are you alright?
If you're not gonna
talk to me, I'll just leave.
Why does it feel like you've
been avoiding me recently?
You easily joke around with Angelito,
while you can't even spare
a bit of attention to me.
Gosh. So he noticed it.
It's not that I'm avoiding you...
It's just...
It so happens that...
I got tired on the way
here. So I'm feeling lethargic.
Binibining Carmelita...
I wanted to ask what you think of
the letter I gave you the other night?
What is this for?
What do I do? What do I even need to say?
I can't even remember where I put it!
Did you like the poem I've written for you?
So it was a poem!
Why didn't I read it immediately?
He'll get upset if he learns
that I lost the poem he made.
I apologize. I haven't read it yet.
We became so busy with taking
care of Helena and packing things.
When you do get the chance to read it,
I hope you'll tell me what you think.
Just make sure you take care of yourself.
My only wish is to see you doing well.
- A blue envelope?
- Uh-huh.
I don't think I saw something
like that at the convent.
OMG! I lost Juanito's letter!
Good morning, ladies.
- Doña Soledad, I will take care of those!
- I'll go over there with Esmeralda.
Who is she?
Have you forgotten who she is, Miss?
She is Esmeralda, your former housekeeper.
Your father summoned her
again to keep watch and...
Discipline the workers at the hacienda.
Someone is spreading
lies about Don Alejandro.
Miss, a letter came for you.
My beloved Carmelita,
I wanted to meet you at the pier yesterday,
but I learned that the
Alfonso family was also there.
It may hurt me,
but I know that you are just following your
father's order to spend time with Juanito.
I know I'm still the one in your heart.
I wish to see you tomorrow
outside the church for Thanksgiving.
With love, Leandro Flores.
Carmelita, let's meet at the church.
I'll accompany Maria first.
My brother Eduardo is waiting for Maria.
Alright, you can go
ahead. I'll follow soon.
Come here, you.
And what are you doing here?
Why, am I not allowed in here?
I know you like Theresita.
I do have feelings for
Theresita, but I know it isn't right.
Because of your status in life?
Do you think Theresita
will like me as well?
I don't have the courage
to admit my feelings.
And I know when I come of age, my
parents will choose a girl for me to marry.
You know, it's better if
you'll be true to yourself.
And if you are ever
arranged into a marriage...
My only advice is to follow your heart.
Is that why you don't want
your wedding to my brother to happen?
Because there's someone else in your heart?
It's not that I don't like Juanito...
To be honest...
I'm actually falling for him.
But...
I know, deep inside...
We are not meant for each other.
Theresita.
Good day to you, Mr. Angelito.
Good day to you as well, Theresita.
Alright. I'll leave you two be.
Miss!
It seems like...
I don't need to wish for anything tonight.
Because my wish just came true.
To see you.
I almost forgot! He told me
in the letter to meet him here.
Don Alejandro and Doña Soledad caught
Mr. Juanito and Miss Helena together!
What?
Let's go!
Is it true that it was your idea
to bring Helena and Juanito closer?
I am the reason behind all this.
Is this enough evidence to prove
your treachery to my daughter?!
Mind your tongue, Alejandro!
It's true that I was the one who brought
Juanito and Helena closer together.
It's also true that I don't want
the marriage to continue.
Because I am in love with Leandro.
It's not just Juanito
that you need to protect.
Your family needs you as well.
You mean to say...
Come here!
Miss!
Where's Juanito?
I'm not sure but...
he told me...
He will get some air
where everything started.
Eduardo says there's trouble
at Alfonso's estate.
What?
Go ahead! Bring me to court!
I will fight for the truth!